scottslawnservice.com 2005-12-31

# Scotts LawnService - Privacy Policy

| 

## the Scotts Company online privacy policy

The Scotts Company takes your privacy seriously and is committed to safeguarding your privacy online. Because we do gather certain types of information from visitors to our sites, we have developed a privacy statement to help you understand the terms and conditions surrounding the collection and use of that information. This statement discloses the types of information we gather, how it is used, and how you can gain access to and edit any data that we've collected about you at any time.

### Guiding Principles

The Scotts Company respects the privacy of individuals who visit our Web sites, send us email, or participate in features/services we offer online. Accordingly, our policy regarding online privacy has been developed using the following guiding principles:

  * Scotts maintains a strict “no-spam” policy. Subscribers to our email services or any other feature/service found on a Scotts Company Web site (scotts.com, miracle-gro.com, ortho.com, roundup.com, osmocote.com, scottslawnservice.com etc.) will not receive unsolicited email messages from Scotts.
  * Scotts collects information online primarily to provide our visitors with a more relevant experience on our sites. When doing so, we will make every reasonable effort to avoid excessive or irrelevant collection of data.
  * Scotts will take reasonable physical, electronic, and managerial measures to safeguard and secure any information you provide to us (e.g., data will be stored in protected databases on secured servers with restricted access).
  * Scotts will not share any information you've provided to us with anyone without your consent other than to provide the service you've requested. At the time you register for any such service, you will be notified of, and asked to consent to, the sharing of your information with any particular third party necessary to the provision of the requested service.

### Information Collected

  * Non-Personally Identifiable Data: Any time you visit a Scotts Web site, we may gather certain non-personally identifiable information regarding the means you use to access our site. This information may include the type and version of your browser, your service provider, you IP address, and any search engine you may have used to locate the site. We use this information to help diagnose problems with our server, administer the Web site, and compile broad statistical data. In addition, The Scotts Company gathers certain navigational information about where you go on our Web sites. This information enables us to determine which areas of the Web sites are most frequently visited and helps us to tailor the sites to the needs and interests of our online visitors. In addition, this tracking data may be used to tailor information presented to you on our sites based on your previous use of the sites and your interests in particular topics.
  * Information Voluntarily Provided: Any information you provide to us (i.e., name, email address, etc.) when you enroll in one of our Email Reminder Services, request information, register on our site, enter one of our contests, or use any of the other interactive portions of our Web sites, is securely maintained on our Web server and internal systems. This information may be used to provide you with information you've requested about our company, our products and our services, or to provide you with special notices. When we request information on our sites, some requests are marked as “Required”; this information is necessary to allow you to participate in the program or service you've requested. You may opt out of receiving future communications at any time (see Opt-Out Procedures below). This data may also be used to tailor your experience on our sites by providing aggregated information from information you provide us (such as demographic data) for use in updating and maintaining our sites. This aggregated information will not be shared with others except as noted below (see the “Disclosure of Personal Information” and “Use of Cookies” sections).
  * Information Collected from Other Sources: To help us better understand and respond to your needs and interests, Scotts may in the future receive information about you from other sources. Scotts will ask any provider of such information to represent and warrant that the information has been gathered and maintained in accordance with all state and federal laws. Any such information will be maintained by Scotts in accordance with the standards set forth in this privacy policy along with other personal information you've provided.

### How We Communicate with You

Scotts may send authorized communications to you on the basis of the information you provide to us through email or regular mail. We will not contact you by telephone, fax, or other means unless you have explicitly requested us to contact you in that manner. You may also opt out of email and regular mail communications from us at any time (see “Opt-Out Procedures” below).

### Disclosure of Personal Information

Scotts understands the importance of your privacy. We collect and maintain the personal information of our consumers for the use of The Scotts Company and its subsidiaries. We do not sell, rent, or trade consumer information to third parties, other than as described below, and never without your consent.

  * Business Partners: The Scotts Company may partner with select retailers and other companies at various times to provide expanded services to our site visitors. As part of such a relationship, Scotts may share with these companies the use of certain interactive Web site functions (e.g., the Email Reminder Service). Information provided by site visitors through the use of such interactive functions may be available to both The Scotts Company and its partners.
  * Agents: Scotts may use other companies and individuals to perform certain functions on our behalf. Examples include administering email services and running special promotions. Such parties only have access to the personal information needed to perform these functions and may not use or store the information for any other purpose. Subscribers or site visitors will never receive unsolicited email messages from agents working on our behalf.
  * Business Transfers: In the event that Scotts sells or transfers a particular portion of its business assets, consumer information may be one of the business assets transferred as part of the transaction. If substantially all of the assets of The Scotts Company are acquired, consumer information may be transferred as part of the acquisition.
  * Compliance with Law/Safety: Scotts may disclose specific personal information based on a good-faith belief that such disclosure is necessary to comply with or conform to the law or that such disclosure is necessary to protect the users of our Web sites, the sites themselves, or the public.
  * With Consent: Other than as set forth in this Privacy Policy, you will be notified when any personally identifiable information about you may be shared with third parties, and you will be given the opportunity to decline to share that information.

### Policies on Children

Children under the age of 13 are welcome to use The Scotts Company Web sites. However, we will ask that a registrant under the age of 13 obtain the approval of a parent or guardian before they become fully registered with one of our Web sites.

### Use of Cookies

Scotts may use a browser feature known as a “cookie.” Cookies are small files placed on your hard drive that assist Scotts in providing you with a customized browsing experience. Scotts uses cookies to provide you with the convenience of not having to reenter information, such as user IDs and passwords, multiple times during your visits to the Scotts Web sites. Cookies can also be utilized to help Scotts provide you with information targeted to your interests, based upon your prior browsing on Scotts Web sites. The “help” section of the toolbar on most browsers will inform you on how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you upon the receipt of a new cookie, or how to disable the use of cookies completely. As the Scotts Web sites have been designed to take advantage of the use of cookies, should you configure your browser to decline their use, certain features of the Scotts Web sites may not function correctly and you may be required to reenter any user IDs and passwords more frequently.

### Accessing The Scotts Company Web Sites from Outside of the United States

If you are visiting a Scotts Company Web site from a location outside of the United States, your connection will be through and to servers located in the United States. Any information you provide during your visit will be processed and maintained on our Web server and other internal systems located within the United States.

### External Links

The Scotts Company Web sites contain links to other sites. Scotts is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites. To help ensure the protection of your privacy, Scotts recommends that you review the privacy policy of any site you visit via a link from one of Scotts' Web sites.

### Passwords

The personal data record created through your registration with a Scotts Web site can only be accessed with the unique password associated with that record. To protect the integrity of the information contained in this record, you should not disclose or otherwise reveal you password to third parties.

### Public Forums

The Scotts Company Web sites may make chat rooms, forum, message boards, and/or news groups available to its users at various times. Please remember that, unless otherwise stated, any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information, and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information in these areas.

### Opt-Out Procedures

You may always opt out of receiving future communications from The Scotts Company. Our sites allow users to opt out of receiving such communications at the point where personal information is requested, or through other means as identified.

### Correcting, Updating, and Removing Information

Scotts supports the individual's right to protect their privacy. Accordingly, personal information you provide us will be made available for your review. Additionally, you may update, modify, or remove this information at any time by doing any of the following:

  * Accessing and modifying your personal information through the Scotts personal information manager application/tool.
  * Sending your updated information by email to [consumer.services@scotts.com](mailto:consumer.services@scotts.com).
  * Using the “Contact Scotts” form.
  * Calling us toll-free at (800) 543-8873.

### Notification of Changes

This privacy policy may be revised over time as features are added to the Web sites and as Internet privacy standards evolve. To ensure that you are fully informed about how your personal information is used, our privacy policy will always be available for review on our Web sites. If we make any substantial changes in the way we use your personal information, we will notify you by posting a prominent announcement on our pages.

### Contacting the Web Sites

If you have questions concerning this privacy policy or the practices of these sites, you may contact us at:

Email: [webservices@scotts.com](mailto:webservices@scotts.com)

The Scotts Company  
14111 Scottslawn Road  
Marysville, Ohio 43041 

back to top  
---|---
